Marc Rodriguez

Seattle, WA 98112 | (706) 877-8958 | marc.herman.rodriguez@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Website</u>

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Background in merchandising, prioritizes completing tasks under pressure, meets deadlines and delivers quality products that are accurate. Background as an English teacher abroad, experienced working on a cross-cultural team. Passionate about learning new things and helping others learn.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML React Rails
CSS Redux ActiveRecord
JavaScript Ruby Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

BeatMachine - Frontend Github | Backend Github | Demo

Programmable drum sequencer with the ability to save beats to your profile and view and comment on other user's beats.

- Used Firebase Storage to handle uploading and storage of audio sample
- Decoded and buffered audio, scheduled samples to play, changed gain, panning and pitch using Web Audio API
- Utilized Redux to manage a large amount of state
- Created custom modal, used it for all user input forms

What's in the Fridge? - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

Users can find recipes based on what items they have loaded in their fridge.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Queried 3rd party database using asynchronous JavaScript to populate recipes for the app
- Used Bootstrap for most of the styling on the app
- Modelled custom database schema and REST API with ActiveRecord, ActiveModel Serializers, SQLite, and Ruby on Rails to store and organize all data for app

RELEVANT SKILLS

Cross Functional Collaboration: Collaborated across company to ensure that sales has all materials and info to successfully market products and services

Customer Service: Investigated and resolved any customer escalations

Quality Assurance: Assured accuracy of promotional details represented in the point of sale systems

Troubleshooting: Experienced in systematically narrowing down a problem to its root cause

Learning Agility: Learned how to use a complicated proprietary database and its idiosyncrasies in a short amount of time

EXPERIENCE

Merchandising Wireless Advocates, Seattle, WA	MAY 2019 - MAR 2021
Customer Service Various including Call Center, Barista and Retail, Seattle, Augusta, New Zealand	2015 – 2018
English as a Second Language Teacher Various Schools, Taipei, Taiwan & Seoul, Korea	2012 - 2014
EDUCATION	
Flatiron School, Seattle, WA Software Engineering Graduate	APR 2021 – JUL 2021
Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA B.A. Music with an emphasis in Recording Technology	MAY 2009
Personal Interests	